# **BRIAN CHILDS**

GRAPHIC ARTIST & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

720-284-2875 brianchilds22@gmail.com https://brianchilds-22.github.io/ Updated-Portfolio/

## **SUMMARY**

A Graphic Artist focusing on Full Stack Development with a passion for creating clean code and user-friendly applications. Also a versatile team player with proven success in management, customer service and crossteam collaboration. Proficient in the MERN Stack; flexible, fast learner bringing curiosity and passion to every project. With several years of experience and a newly obtained completion certificate from the University of Denver's Coding Bootcamp.

## SKILLS

HTML	****
CSS	****
Bootstrap	***
Wordpress	***
Javascript	***
Jquery	***
Node	***
MySQL	***
Google Dev Tools	***
VS Code	***
Photoshop	****
Illustrator	****
Indesign	****
Acrobat	****
After Effects	***
Premier	***
Dreamweaver	***
Mail Chimp	***

## **EXPERIENCE**

## FREELANCE GRAPHIC ARTIST PETROLIA MARKETING

2017— PRESENT Englewood, co

Freelance graphic artist /marketing business owner with vast experience in developing strong customer relationships, meeting strict deadlines and making all business decisions. Including project and time management, stay motivated, conflict resolution, using leadership, adaptability, teamwork and creativity as an acting business owner and operator.

#### **KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS:**

- Creating multiple brands from conceptualization to digital and print deliverables
- Developing and implementing marketing strategies for small business
- ◆ Performance bonus Automotive Internet Marketing
- ◆ Graphic Design and Print Production services for small business

### DIGITAL MARKETING MANAGER MEDICAL SALES COLLEGE

2015—2016 Littleton. Co

Developed, implemented, and tracked digital marketing campaigns for social media and online presence. Identified trends and optimized performance resulting in followers and higher enrollment.

#### **KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS:**

- Developed LinkedIn and Twitter pages resulting in thousands of followers.
- ◆ Marketing led to higher enrollments and eventually more campuses.

## ART DIRECTOR / PROJECT MANAGER XL EDGE

2012—2015 Englewood. Co

Art Director and Project Manager responsibilities, conceptual design for digital and print marketing, production schedule management for monthly publication.

#### **KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS:**

- ◆ Promoted and managed 3 people and production schedule.
- Worked with large brands like General Mills, Kraft, Unilever and Kroger.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE: DENVER UNIVERSITY**

DENVER. CO

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

#### BACHELOR'S DEGREE: COLORADO INSTITUTE OF ART

DENVER, CO

A Graphic Design and Visual Communications Major. Classes included: Art Direction, Drawing, Typography, Video Editing and Digital and Printing Design.